[
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'07-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What type of routing protocol builds a topological map of the network and selects the shortest path using algorithms?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Static",
    "b": "Dynamic",
    "c": "Hybrid",
    "d": "Link-state",
    "correct_ans": "d",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'08-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What term refers to a group of switches managed as a single entity where VLAN information is shared across the switches?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Trunking ",
    "b": "Stacking ",
    "c": "Spanning tree",
    "d": "VTP",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'09-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which mechanism is used to prevent switching loops on a network with redundant paths?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "VLSM ",
    "b": "STP ",
    "c": "VTP ",
    "d": "OSPF",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'10-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What protocol operates at layer 2 of the OSI model to filter unknown MAC addresses and only forward frames to ports containing the intended destination?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "STP ",
    "b": "DTP ",
    "c": "VTP ",
    "d": "ARP",
    "correct_ans": "d",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'11-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What technology allows a switch port to carry traffic for multiple VLANs?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Routing ",
    "b": "Trunking ",
    "c": "Multicasting ",
    "d": "Link aggregation",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'6-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which routing protocol uses the Bellman-Ford algorithm to determine the best path for routing data?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "RIP ",
    "b": "BGP ",
    "c": "OSPF",
    "d": "IS-IS",
    "correct_ans": "a",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'7-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which mechanism helps prevent loops within a layer 2 network by shutting down redundant paths?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "STP ",
    "b": "Multicast ",
    "c": "Trunking ",
    "d": "LACP",
    "correct_ans": "a",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'8-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "In a three tier hierarchical network model, which devices form the distribution layer?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Core routers",
    "b": "ToR switches",
    "c": "Aggregation switches",
    "d": "Access switches",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'9-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which type of routing protocol only shares routing information with neighbors?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Exterior Gateway Protocol",
    "b": "Interior Gateway Protocol",
    "c": "Autonomous System",
    "d": "Access Protocol",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'10-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which layer 2 redundancy protocol provides link aggregation to increase bandwidth between switches?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "STP ",
    "b": "VLSM",
    "c": "VRRP ",
    "d": "LACP",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'17-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What mechanism helps prevent switching loops at layer 2 but also defines root bridge priority?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "VTP ",
    "b": "ARP ",
    "c": "STP ",
    "d": "DTP",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'18-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which routing protocol uses Dijkstra's algorithm to determine routing information?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "BGP ",
    "b": "OSPF",
    "c": "RIPv2 ",
    "d": "EIGRP",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'19-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What are subsections of a network sharing same initial bits of subnet mask in CIDR notation called?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Subnets ",
    "b": "Supernets",
    "c": "VLANs ",
    "d": "Links",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'20-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which protocol adds security to remote connections by encrypting traffic through a public network?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "HTTPS ",
    "b": "SSH ",
    "c": "SCP ",
    "d": "SSL",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'21-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which type of VLAN carries traffic for multiple subnets in a common VLAN?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Data ",
    "b": "Native ",
    "c": "Default",
    "d": "Management",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'22-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What mechanism constructs a layer 2 frame to encapsulate packet data?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "ARP ",
    "b": "STP ",
    "c": "Switching ",
    "d": "Tagging",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'23-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What are unique sender/receiver port pairings at the transport layer called that help in multiplexing?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Labels ",
    "b": "Sessions ",
    "c": "Streams",
    "d": "Sockets",
    "correct_ans": "d",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'24-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "In what kind of network are all interconnected devices are within same collision domain?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "SAN ",
    "b": "WAN ",
    "c": "LAN ",
    "d": "MAN",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'25-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What field in an Ethernet frame represents application layer data passed down though the OSI layers?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Trailer ",
    "b": "Payload ",
    "c": "Checksum",
    "d": "Prefix",
    "correct_ans": "b",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'26-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "If no routing protocols are enabled on router interfaces, what type of route is used to determine where packets are forwarded?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Static ",
    "b": "Dynamic",
    "c": "Floating",
    "d": "Access",
    "correct_ans": "a",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'27-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What important device acts as the connection point between network segments?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Repeater ",
    "b": "Bridge ",
    "c": "Router",
    "d": "Gateway",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'28-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What mechanism allows a switch to determine the MAC address associated with an incoming frame's source IP address?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "CDP ",
    "b": "SNMP ",
    "c": "ARP",
    "d": "STP",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'29-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which OSI layer is concerned with logical addressing required to deliver packets across interconnected networks?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Data Link",
    "b": "Transport ",
    "c": "Session ",
    "d": "Network",
    "correct_ans": "d",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'30-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What tool is critical for network management and remote monitoring of device statistics?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "SSH ",
    "b": "VTP ",
    "c": "SNMP ",
    "d": "Telnet",
    "correct_ans": "c",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'31-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "What mechanism is used to mark frames between VLAN attached hosts so that they traverse a common trunk without interference?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "Tagging ",
    "b": "Sequencing",
    "c": "Acknowledging",
    "d": "Caching",
    "correct_ans": "a",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  },
  {
    "_id": "30-nov-2023-15'32-@Sanket-Arekar",
    "question": "Which protocol supports automatic redistribution of routing information making configuration easier?",
    "question-image": "",
    "a": "RIP",
    "b": "OSPF",
    "c": "BGP ",
    "d": "EIGRP",
    "correct_ans": "d",
    "answer-image": "",
    "topic": "Computer Networks"
  }
]
